This is a librivox recording all librivox recordings are in the public
domain for more information or to volunteer please visit librivox.org this recording by jay hall
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum Chapter 7 The Journey to the Great
Oz They were obliged to camp out that night under a large tree in the forest,
for there were no houses near. The tree made a good, thick covering to protect
them from the dew, and the Tin Woodman chopped a great pile of wood with his
axe and Dorothy built a splendid fire that warmed her and made her feel less
lonely. She and Toto ate the last of their bread, and now she did not know
what they would do for breakfast. “If you wish,” said the Lion, “I will go into the
forest and kill a deer for you. You can roast it by the fire, since your tastes
are so peculiar that you prefer cooked food, and then you will have a very good
breakfast.” “Don’t! Please don’t beg the Tin Woodman.
“I should certainly weep if you kill a poor deer, and then my jaws would rust
again.” But the Lion went away into the forest and found his own supper, and no
one ever knew what it was, for he didn’t mention it. And the Scarecrow found a
tree full of nuts and filled Dorothy’s basket with him so that she would not be
hungry for a long time.
She thought that this was very kind and thoughtful of the Scarecrow, but he
laughed heartedly at the awkward way in which the poor creature picked up the
nuts. His padded hands were so clumsy and the nuts were so small that he dropped
almost as many as he put in the basket.
But the Scarecrow did not mind how long it took him to fill the basket or it
enabled him to keep away from the fire, as he feared a spark might get into his
straw and burn him up. So he kept a good distance away from the flames, and only
came near to cover Dorothy with dry leaves when she lay down to sleep.
These kept her very snug and warm, and she slept soundly until morning. When it
was daylight, the girl bathed her face in a little rippling brook, and soon after
they all started toward the Emerald City was to be an invented day for the
travelers. They had hardly been walking an hour when they saw before them a
great ditch that crossed the road and divided the forest as far as they could
see on either side. It was a very wide ditch, and when they crept up to the edge
and looked into it they could see that it was also very deep, and there were
many big, jagged rocks at the bottom. The sides were so steep that none of them
could climb down, and for a moment it seemed that their journey must end. “What
shall we do?” asked Dorothy despairingly. “I haven’t the faintest idea,” said the Tin
Woodman, and the Lion shook his shaggy mane and looked thoughtfully But the
Scarecrow said, “We cannot fly, that is certain. Neither we can we jump down into
the great ditch. Therefore, if we cannot jump over it, we must stop where we are.” “I
think I could jump over it,” said the Cowardly Lion, after measuring the
distance carefully in his mind. “Then we are all right,” answered the Scarecrow
where you can carry us all over on your
back, one at a time.” “Well, I’ll try it,” said
the Lion. “Who will go first?” “I will declare the Scarecrow, “for, if you found
that you could not jump over the gulf, Dorothy would be killed, or the Tin
Woodman badly dented on the rocks below.
But if I am on your back it will not matter so much, for the fall would not
hurt me at all.” “I am terribly afraid of falling, myself,”
said the Cowardly Lion, “but I suppose there is nothing to do but try it.
So get on my back and we will make the attempt.” The Scarecrow sat upon the Lions
back, and the big beast walked to the edge of the gulf and crouched down. “Why
don’t you run and jump?” asked the Scarecrow. “Because that isn’t the way we
Lions do things,” he replied. Then giving a great spring, he shot through the air and
landed safely on the other side. They were all greatly pleased to see how
easily he did it, and after the Scarecrow had gotten down from his back the Lion
sprang across the ditch again.
Dorothy thought she would go next; so she took Toto in her arms and climbed on the
Lions back, holding tightly to his mane with one hand.
The next moment it seemed as if she were flying through the air; and then, before
she had time to think about it, she was safe on the other side. The Lion went
back a third time and got the Tin Woodman, and then they all sat down for a
few moments to give the beast a chance to rest, for his great leaps had made his
breast short, and he panted like a big dog that has been running too long.
They found the forest very thick on this side, and it looked dark and gloomy. After
the line had rested they started along the road of yellow brick, silently
wondering, each in his own mind, if ever they would come to the end of the woods
and reach the bright sunshine again. To add to their discomfort, they soon heard
strange noises in the depths of the forest, and the Lion whispered to them
that it was in this part of the country that the collie das lived. “What are the
calli das asked the girl.
“They are monstrous beasts with bodies like bears and heads like tigers,” replied
the Lion, “and with claws so long and sharp that they could tear me in two as
easily as I could kill Toto. I’m terribly afraid of the Kali das I’m not surprised
that you are,” returned Dorothy. “They must be dreadful beasts.” The Lion was about to
reply when suddenly they came to another gulf across the road. But this one was so
broad and deep that the Lion knew at once he could not leap across it. So they
sat down to consider what they should do, and after serious thought the Scarecrow
said: “Here was a great tree, standing close to the ditch.
If the Tin Woodman can chop it down, so that it will fall to the other side, we
can walk across it easily.” “That is a first-rate idea,” said the Lion. “One would
almost suspect you had brains in your head, instead of straw.” The Woodman set to
work at once, and so sharp was his axe that the tree was soon chopped nearly
through. Then the Lion put his strong front legs against the tree and pushed
with all his might, and slowly the big tree tipped and fell with a crash across
the ditch, with its top branches on the other side. They had just started to
cross this queer bridge when a sharp growl made them all look up, and
their horror they saw running towards them two great beasts with bodies like
bears and heads like tigers. “They are the Kelly DAWs said the Cowardly Lion,
beginning to tremble. “Quick!” cried the Scarecrow. “Let us cross over.” So Dorothy went first,
holding Toto in her arms, the Tin Woodman followed, and the Scarecrow came next. The
Lion, although he was certainly afraid, turned to face the collied oz and then
he gave so loud and terrible a roar that Dorothy screamed and the Scarecrow fell
over backwards while even the fierce beasts stopped short and looked at him
in surprise. But, seeing that they were bigger than the Lion, and remembering
that there were two of them and only one of him, the Kali DAWs again rushed
forward, and the Lion crossed over the tree and turned to see what they would
do next. Without stopping an instant the fierce beasts also began to cross the
tree. And the Lion said to Dorothy: “We are lost, for they were surely tear us to
pieces with her sharp claws. But stand close behind me, and I will fight them as
long as I am alive.” “Wait a minute!” called the Scarecrow. He had been
thinking what was best to be done, and now he asked the Woodman to chop away at
the end of the tree that rested on their side of the ditch. The Tin Woodman began
to use his axe at once, and, just as the two collied odds were nearly across, the
tree fell with a crash into the gulf, carrying the ugly, snarling brutes with
it, and both were dashed to pieces on the sharp rocks at the bottom. “Well,” said the
Cowardly Lion, drawing in a long breath of relief, “I see we are going to live a
little while longer, and I am glad of it, for it must be a very uncomfortable
thing not to be alive. Those creatures frightened me so badly that my heart is
beating yet.” “Ah,” said the Tin Woodman sadly, “I wish I had a heart to beat.” This
adventure made the travelers more anxious than ever to get out of the
forest, and they walked so fast that Dorothy became tired, and had to ride on
the lines back. To the great joy the trees became thinner the farther they
advanced, and in the afternoon they suddenly came upon a broad river, flowing
swiftly just before them.
On the other side of the water they could see the road of yellow brick
running through a beautiful country, with green meadows dotted with bright flowers
and all the road bordered with trees hanging full of delicious fruits. They
were greatly pleased to see this delightful country before them. “How shall
we cross the river ask Dorothy. “That is easily done,” replied the Scarecrow. “The
Tin Woodman must build us a raft, so that we can float to the other side.” So the
Woodman took his axe and began to chop down small trees to make a raft, and
while he was busy at this the Scarecrow found on the riverbank a tree full of
fine fruit. This pleased Dorothy, who had eaten nothing but nuts all day, and she
made a hearty meal of the ripe fruit. But it takes time to make a raft, even when
one is as industrious and untiring as the Tin Woodman, and when night came the
work was not done. So they found a cozy place under the trees where they slept
well until the morning; and Dorothy dreamed of the Emerald City, and of the
good Wizard Oz, who would soon send her back to her own home again end of
chapter 7 This is a LibriVox